Sai Srinath Josyula

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sai-srinath-josyula/ || http://www.saisrinathjosyula.com || https://github.com/sjosyul1

1265 E University Drive, App 1055, Tempe, Arizona, 85281. | 602-245-5945 | srinath.5893@gmail.com

Career Summary:

Software Development professional with 2 years' experience in IT industry. Worked on a product called Finacle for over 1.5 years. Graduate Student looking for opportunities in Software Development and Big Data Analytics. I have hands-on experience on projects like Java, Python Development, Django, AWS, Google Cloud, Spark-ML, Graphx, Streaming, SQL, Ambari, Kafka, Flume, Hadoop and Spark Administration On VM, Full Stack Web development.

Education:

Master's in Information Technology Arizona State University, AZ. CGPA: 4/4 Jan 2017- Dec 2018

Related Coursework:

Analyzing Big Data, Advance Data Analytics, Cloud Computing, Advanced SQL Techniques, System Administration of Unix, Software Engineering, Networking, Algorithms and Data Structures.

Skills and Abilities:

Languages: Java, Python, Scala, SQL, C, Bash Script.

Web Technologies: HTML, XML, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, CSS, JSON, Django, JSP, JSF.

Modules and Compo Spark-ML, GraphX, Streaming, SQL, Kafka, Flume, Ambari, HDFS.

Platforms and Tools Linux, Windows, MS Office, Eclipse, Pycharm, IntelliJ, AWS, Cygwin, Putty, BigQuery, AppEngine

Projects:

- Analyzed Big data on cloud. Main aim of the project was to find duplication of questions from Quora question pairs. I have Used Scala for analyzing data and created Spark clusters on AWS. Data Visualization was done using Amazon Quick Sight and Tableau.
- Administration of Hadoop on VM using Hortonworks Distributions. I have setup Hadoop ecosystem on a 4-node cluster on VMware workstation 14 pro.
- Twitter-Review Analysis: Main aim is to provide review analysis of place, food, events etc. through charts. Used Django to provide user interface. Deployed application on Google App Engine, used BigQuery to store Tweets. Google Data Studio to Visualize data. Technologies: Python, Django, Google App Engine, BigQuery, Google Data Studio.
- Multi-Threaded webserver: Main aim is to handle multiple request at once. Deployed the application on AWS. I have used Wireshark to capture network traffic. Technologies: Java, AWS, Networking.
- **SpamHam Analysis:** Main aim of the project was if an email is spam or ham using Spark ML techniques. Built ML pipeline using Spark libraries. **Technologies used are Spark, Scala, Spark ML**
- Built a Meetup portal for ASU polytechnic campus using which students and faculty can organize meetings and share their knowledge. Technologies used JAVA, JDBC, Servlets, HTML, CSS, JavaScript.
- Built a fully functional portal for Photo-voltaic Module certification using **Python**, **Django framework**. Used MSSQL as database and implemented **Stored procedures**, **Cursors**, **Triggers**, **Views**, **Dynamic SQL**.
- Hosmer Medical Analysis: Using ML pipeline Techniques analyzed if a patient had breast cancer. Tech: Spark, Scala.

Work Experience: (Software Engineer)

INTERNSHIP: Infosys, Mysore.

Dec 2014 - April 2015

• Trained in Infosys, Mysore for 5 months on Java, Database Management, Software Engineering, HTML5, CSS3, Java Scripting and Finacle. Completed a Full Stack Web Development project as a part of the training.

Infosys and EdgeVerve:

Apr 2015 - Dec 2016

- Part of Edge Verve, Finacle. It is a banking product developed by Infosys. My work involved **development of Finacle Treasury enhancements, moving configuration of app sever to database** which enabled FT manager.
- Support of custodian account for securities Buy/Sell, Repo and Equity/MF deals and quick setup which automates the setup of various screens like scheme details, swift messages.
- Worked on **Unix and Database** for an application called Finacle Treasury.

Part Time Experience:

Jan 2018 - Dec 2018

• Graduate Service Assistant for Front End Web development subject. This subject deal with HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript and JQuery.